Matthew Lodge // UI & UX Designer

mlodge.me // mattpodge@gmail.com // (+44) 07904 989875 // Milton Keynes, UK

Introduction

Involved in the design industry since 2008, where I started as a Graphic Designer. It soon followed that my interests in digital media lead to roles as a web designer and developer, before naturally finding myself focusing on UI design in the software industry.

I feel my strengths as a UI designer often branch from my interests in the tech and digital media industry. I look for influences from my favourite films and video games, as well as the popular apps people use on a daily basis, to get a sense of how audiences want to interact with software that's important to them. I've also taken a keen interest into accessibility options, learning how best we can cater to as many users as possible.

I'm comfortable working within multi-discipline teams, and am often eager to help out where I can. It hasn't been unknown for me to code working prototypes in order to help developers better understand how a design might work across devices, or to support an idea that others may not be able to visualise.

Outside of work I enjoy socialising with friends, planning cultural trips abroad, and do my best to keep some level of fitness despite my girlfriend's emerging talents as a baker during lockdown.

Experience

Little Star Media // UI & UX Designer

Milton Keynes // July 2020 - August 2020

Little Star Media recently launched an offshoot of their UK based gambling comparison products for a US market. With this release, they required an experienced UX designer to identify and implement opportunities to cater to the users in the US.

With the use of analytical tools and user recordings, I was able to create a roadmap of where improvements could be made to increase engagement with the high turnover of users. This method of user insight was was extremely useful for a product in which we could not entirely rely on a strong returning userbase for 1-to-1 feedback, and I found the results interesting to interpret.

TED Group // Freelance Graphic Designer Milton Keynes // February 2020 - March 2020

As part of my freelance work, TED group employed my services to assist with the increased workload they were experiencing. This work focused primarily around packaging design and merchandising for hospitality parks. This work had a requirement to be completed within prescribed marketing guidelines and as a freelancer I was able to produce a high standard of work meeting all goals within the desired timeline.

Design Skills

- User Interface
- User Experience
- Web Design
- Graphic Design
- Branding & Marketing

Dev Skills

- HTMI
- CSS & SCSS
- Javascript
- React

General Skills

- Agile method
- Design sprints
- Good communication
- Problem solving
- Learn from mistakes

Software & Tools

- Adobe Suite
 - Photoshop
 - Illustrator
 - InDesign
 - o Xd
- Sketch
- InVision

Matthew Lodge // UI & UX Designer

mlodge.me // mattpodge@gmail.com // (+44) 07904 989875 // Milton Keynes, UK

Aiimi // UX Designer

London // July 2019 - January 2020

My UX Designer role at Aiimi found me integrated into the Aiimi Labs team, to improve the user experience and design features of their new B2B product, InsightMaker.

As part of my role I collaborated directly with stakeholders and product owners to gain a better understanding of the product requirements. I also engaged with users in testing and feedback sessions during beta testing, utilising this feedback to ensure this product met the requirements in order to make the product a potential success.

WorkForce Software // UI, UX, & Graphic Designer Milton Keynes // July 2016 - June 2019

WorkForce (then Workplace) was my first role held as a UI Designer, which over time expanded to include duties involving UX design. It was here that I was introduced to the Agile working methodology and all that usually comes with it (sprints, retrospectives, planning etc).

My role as UI designer had me working closely with developers across numerous teams (and continents), often times helping out with translation of my static designs to working prototypes using tools like Sketch and InVision, as well as self coded demos that would often end up ported in to the product themselves.

WorkForce cultivated an environment in which I could learn and grow, and I was able to try my hand at frameworks like Angular and React, without fear of failure.

As well as close working relationships with developers, I worked in tandem with many product owners across the company and felt my advice and expertise was welcomed.

Outside of role responsibilities I fostered friendships with many of the teams I worked alongside, took part in extra curricular hackathons and events, and presented my own talks at monthly brown bag sessions as an ongoing knowledge exchange.

Education

HND Graphic Design & Communication

Milton Keynes College

A-Levels & GCSEs

Denbigh Secondary School

Work History

Workplace Systems

UI & Graphic Designer Jan 2015 - Jul 2016

Incentivesmart

Web Designer & Front End Developer Apr 2013 - Dec 2014

Makita UK

Web & Graphic Designer, & Front End Developer Apr 2010 - Apr 2013

Palmiero Design

Web & Graphic Designer, & Front End Developer Feb 2008 - Mar 2010

References

Available on request